surveyjunkie.com 2014-12-07

# Privacy - Survey Junkie

## YOUR PRIVACY IS IMPORTANT TO US

Market research serves an important function in society. Businesses and governments make better decisions through survey research. As a survey participant, your opinions help companies develop new products, make existing ones better, and improve customer service. 

If you have any privacy questions or concerns, please contact our Privacy Officer via e-mail at (privacy@surveyjunkie.com) or by mail (1200 S Brand Blvd, #112, Los Angeles, CA 91204).

## INFORMATION COLLECTED AND USED

SurveyJunkie.com (SURVEY JUNKIE) collects user-submitted information including name and email address to verify new accounts and send notifications related to SURVEY JUNKIE's services. This web site collects online contact information in various ways, including inquiry forms, registration forms, surveys, and contests. SURVEY JUNKIE collects additional data that is included in member profile submitted by the member voluntarily. When you participate in research, you may be asked for your personal opinions, as well as demographic information, such as your age and household composition. You may refuse to answer certain questions or discontinue participation in a study at any time. Email addresses are used to send notifications related to the service(s) for which you have signed up, including but not limited to: a) an invitation to participate in survey research, b) an invitation to conduct a research survey interview with you, c) validate of answers you gave in a recent survey we conducted, d) an invitation to participate in sponsored programs from our advertisers, and d) notification of updates and to ensure that our records of your personal information are correct. (applicable only to panels). Occasionally, we may contact you also to notify you if you have won a prize draw that we sponsored and/or to ask for your permission to use your personal information for a purpose that was not explained to you when we first collected your personal information. 

Like most web sites, we gather certain non-personal information automatically and store it in various databases, cookies, or log files. This information includes IP (Internet Protocol) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp and clickstream data. We use this information to analyze trends, to prevent creating duplicate accounts, to administer our site, to track users' movements around our site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. To protect against fraud, we may link this automatically-collected data to information submitted.

SURVEY JUNKIE makes reasonable efforts to keep personal information in its possession or control, which is used on an ongoing basis, accurate, complete, current and relevant, based on the most recent information available to us. We rely on you to help us keep your personal information accurate, complete and current by answering our questions honestly.

## Cookies:

A cookie, also known as an HTTP cookie, web cookie, or browser cookie, is a small piece of data sent from a website and stored in a user's web browser while the user is browsing that website. Every time the user loads the website, the browser sends the cookie back to the server to notify the website of the user's previous activity.

We use cookies on our survey site to help us provide you with a better experience along with quality control and validation functions. No personal information is stored on any cookie that we use. Some of the cookies that we use on this site are required because they identify you as a valid member, and they protect access to your profile and account information. The privacy settings of your browser must be configured to allow cookies from (www.surveyjunkie.com) or you will not be able to register on the (www.surveyjunkie.com) panel or access the Members Area of this site. If you wish, you can adjust your browser’s privacy settings to delete cookies upon exiting web sites or when you close your browser. Information stored in cookies will never contain any personally identifiable information. Third parties also place scripts on our site such as analytics providers which may place their own cookies on your system. This data is only collected in the aggregate. Cookies are used to identify a unique user, authentication of the user, store personal preferences, track and personalize offers and promotions.

This site may at times also use Flash Local Shared Objects (LSO), also known as “Flash cookies,” to store some of your preferences, to display content based upon what you view, to personalize your visit, to combat fraud that endangers the quality of research, or to otherwise track your behavior and activities across multiple visits to the site. We use Flash cookies strictly for research purposes only.

Flash cookies are different from browser cookies because of the amount and type of data stored and how the data are stored. The latest versions of popular browsers now allow internet users to manage Flash cookies using browser privacy settings or downloading add-ons.

If your browser does not support these features, then you can manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies or disable their use entirely by visiting Macromedia’s website, the manufacturer of Flash Player, at the following link:

<http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html>

We use optional cookies, through browsers, Flash, and possible software applications for conducting advertising and website research. These cookies are available only to members who have explicitly agreed to participate in our behavioral tracking research program. The cookies keep track of certain online advertisements and web pages that you see, including how frequently the online content that we are measuring is viewed by your computer.

Device Identification technologies assign a unique identifier to a user's computer to identify and track the computer. SURVEY JUNKIE may on some occasions use Device identification technology to collect personal information or track the online activities of computer users. We use the technology, among other things, to assist our clients in ensuring the integrity of survey results. The technology analyses information and data obtained from your computer's web browser and from other publically available data points, including for example the technical settings of your computer, the characteristics of your computer, and your computer's IP address. This data is used to create a unique identifier assigned to your computer. The unique identifier may be an alpha-numeric ID which we retain. We do not retain the information analysed by the technology to create the unique identifier. The technology does not disrupt or interfere with your use or control of your computer and it does not alter, modify or change the settings or functionality of your computer.

In furtherance of our efforts to assist clients in protecting and ensuring the integrity of survey results, we may: 

  1. link or associate your unique identifier to you and any of the information you provide to us;
  2. share your unique identifier with our clients and with other sample or panel providers; and
  3. receive or obtain a unique identifier linked to you from a third party, including without limitation a sample or panel provider or a client of our firm.

Any unique identifier(s) linked to a specific individual will be protected in accordance with this privacy policy. We shall use and distribute the technology in a professional and ethical manner and in accordance with our privacy policy, any statements and/or disclosures made by our firm to you, and applicable laws and industry codes.

In the event that we discover or learn of any unethical conduct in connection with the use of the technology, or that the technology is being used in a manner that is inconsistent with the statements and/or disclosures made by us to respondents or in violation of applicable laws and codes, we will take immediate action to prohibit such unethical conduct and to ensure the proper administration of the technology.

## Third Party Advertising:

A portion of the advertisements seen on SURVEY JUNKIE are delivered to users by third-party advertising partners. These partners may use cookies when showing ads to users. These cookies may be used to determine which site the advertiser's advertisement was displayed on and whether or not the user interacted with the advertisement. This information helps advertising partners deliver targeted advertisements that will be most relevant to you. These cookies are not linked to personal information. SURVEY JUNKIE does not have access to the cookies placed by third parties. SURVEY JUNKIE’s privacy statement applies only to SURVEY JUNKIE and does not apply to use of cookies by any third parties.

## INFORMATION SHARED

We promise to protect your privacy and treat the information you give us as confidential. The information you provide will be used primarily for research purposes. We will not release your personal information to any third party without your consent. We will never try to sell you anything and we will never sell your personal data to anyone.

Your survey responses are combined with the responses of others who participate in surveys and those gathered responses are reported to clients that commissioned the study. We will never intentionally report your individual survey responses, except as described below. Your survey responses may be collected, stored or processed by our affiliated companies or non-affiliated service providers, both within and outside United States. They are contractually bound to keep any information they collect and disclose to us or we collect and disclose to them confidential and must protect it with security standards and practices that are equivalent to our own.

We inform our employees about our policies and procedures regarding confidentiality, security and privacy, and we emphasize the importance of complying with them. Our security procedures are consistent with generally accepted commercial standards used to protect personal information.

Unless we have your permission or are required by law, we will only share the personal data you provide with other SURVEY JUNKIE agents, contractors or our business partners for the purposes of performing services for SURVEY JUNKIE. SURVEY JUNKIE may share aggregated data with others. Aggregated data does not include personally identifiable information.

SURVEY JUNKIE may also disclose account information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating SURVEY JUNKIE’s Terms of Use or may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) SURVEY JUNKIE's rights or property, other SURVEY JUNKIE users, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. SURVEY JUNKIE may disclose or access account information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it and for administrative and other purposes that we deem necessary to maintain, service, and improve our products and services.

In addition to keeping your survey responses confidential, we will never sell, share, rent or otherwise intentionally transfer your name, address, telephone number or e-mail address to our clients, other market research companies, direct marketing companies or anyone else.

The only exceptions when we may disclose your personal information or survey responses to third parties are as follows: a) you request or consent to sharing your identifying information and individual responses with the third parties for a specified purpose, b) in accordance with the ESOMAR guidelines, we provide your responses to a third party who is contractually bound to keep the information disclosed confidential and use it only for research or statistical purposes, in the rare but possible circumstance that the information is subject to disclosure pursuant to judicial or other government subpoenas, warrants, orders or for similar legal or regulatory requirements. 

In certain circumstances, SURVEY JUNKIE may share demographic information and aggregate usage information in a non-personally identifiable fashion to advertisers or other third parties for the purpose of delivering more targeted advertising, products and services to members. SURVEY JUNKIE reserves the right to transfer personal information to a successor in interest that acquires rights to that information as a result of the sale of SURVEY JUNKIE or part of its assets to that successor in interest. 

## LINKS TO OTHER SITES

SURVEY JUNKIE expects its partners, advertisers and affiliates to respect the privacy of our users. Be aware, however, that third parties, including our partners, advertisers, affiliates and other content providers accessible through our site, may have their own privacy and data collection policies and practices. 

Also, via our site you may be introduced to, or be able to access, information, Web sites, features, contests or sweepstakes offered by other parties. SURVEY JUNKIE is not responsible for the actions or policies of such third parties. You should check the applicable privacy policies of those third parties when providing information on a feature or page operated by a third party.

Please be aware that if you voluntarily disclose Personally Identifiable Information on message boards or in chat areas, that information can be viewed publicly and can be collected and used by third parties without our knowledge and may result in unsolicited messages from other individuals or third parties. Such activities are beyond the control of SURVEY JUNKIE and this policy.

## Children Under 13

SURVEY JUNKIE does not knowingly collect or solicit Personally Identifiable Information from or about children under 13 except as permitted by law. If we discover we have received any information from a child under 13 in violation of this policy, we will delete that information immediately. If you believe SURVEY JUNKIE has any information from or about anyone under 13, please contact us.

## SECURITY

This web site has security measures in place to protect against loss, misuse and/or alteration of the information that you provide. Furthermore, we have taken every precaution technically possible to prevent any unauthorized access to the contents of this web server.

## OPT-OUT/MODIFY

SURVEY JUNKIE provides every user with the opportunity to opt-out of receiving future communications, change and modify information previously provided,. Should a member of SURVEY JUNKIE wish to change and modify information previously provided, they can log on and make the required changes to their account profile. Members may submit a support ticket indicating their email address if they wish to stop receiving notification emails from the site or cancel their membership to the site altogether. There are also instructions on how to opt-out of receiving future emails included at the bottom of every email sent from SURVEY JUNKIE. SURVEY JUNKIE will honor all requests for cancellation, and you will not receive any more emails within 10 business days of the request.

## Contacting "Survey Junkie"

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this web site, or your dealings with this web site, please locate and click the “Contact Us” link on our site. You may also send any notifications to us at the following address: SURVEY JUNKIE, Attn: User Privacy, 1200 S. Brand Blvd. #112, Los Angeles, CA 91204

## Legal Disclosure

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web site.

## POLICY CHANGES

SURVEY JUNKIE reserves the right to change this privacy policy at any time, so please review this policy frequently.

This Privacy Policy was last revised on October 15, 2014.
